His only weapon is his will to survive.
Behind Enemy Lines is a action, drama, thriller film directed by John Moore.
While flying a routine reconnaissance mission over Bosnia, fighter pilot Lt.
Chris Burnett photographs something he wasn't supposed to see and gets shot down behind
enemy lines, where he must outrun an army led by a ruthless Serbian general.
With time running out and a deadly tracker on his trail, Burnett's commanding officer, Admiral
Reigart, decides to risk his career and launch a renegade rescue mission to save his life.
Lt. Chris 'Longhorn' Burnett, played by Owen Wilson.
Admiral Leslie Reigart, Commander Adriatic Battle Group, played by Gene Hackman.
Lt. Jeremy 'Smoke' Stackhouse, played by Gabriel Macht.
General Miroslav Lokar, played by Olek Krupa.
Tracker (Sasha), played by Vladimir Mashkov.
Bazda, played by Marko Igonda.
Behind Enemy Lines is a 2001 American action war film directed by John Moore in
his directorial debut, and starring Owen Wilson and Gene Hackman.
The film tells the story of Lieutenant Chris Burnett, an American naval flight officer
who is shot down over Bosnia and uncovers genocide during the Bosnian War.
Meanwhile, the rear admiral commanding the carrier strike group to which he is assigned is
struggling to gain approval to launch a combat search and rescue mission to save Burnett.
The plot is loosely based on a 1995 incident involving
Scott O'Grady that occurred during the war.
Released on November 30, 2001, Behind Enemy Lines
received generally mixed reviews from critics.
It was a box office success, taking in $121.7 million
worldwide against a $40 million budget.
The film launched a franchise that includes three
sequels, all of them direct-to-video.
The film explores themes of sniper, war crimes, bosnia and
herzegovina, rescue mission, u.s. navy.
The tone is emotional and intense.